Guide to the Anderson Todd architectural academic and career papers, 1943-1995 UA 314
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series X: Slides and Photographs, 1949-1988, 163977
  - International Travel, 165223
    - Egypt, 165327 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ely, 165328 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - England, 165329 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - H. Chipping Camden, Ely, 165330 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mexico, 165331 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Mt. Fuji, Japan, 165332 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nara, Japan, 165333 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Neutra, Lawrence, 165334 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - various: Honduras, DC, Tegucigalca, 165335 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Winchester to London, 165336 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified/undated, 165337 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Photos, June 1981, 165338 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Travel maps and itineraries, 165339 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Domestic Travel, 165224
    - "Taliesin Ukst" and Grand Canyon, Jan. 1950, 165340 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Mississippi River Plantation Houses, 1956, 165341 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Boston/Chicago/Houston, 1962, 165342 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified, 1963, 165343 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Bear Run, PA, June 1971, 165344 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - St. Louis, Dearborn, June 1971, 165345 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Various locations, 1971, 165346 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Chatham Hall, Weston, Mississippi, May 1973, 165347 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Williamsburg, VA, May 25-27, 1974, 165348 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - New Haven, 1977, 165349 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Dallas, Spring 1978, 165350 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Chicago Trip, Nov. 1978, 165351 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Arizona, Feb 1985, 165352 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Santa Fe, Fall 1985, 165353 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Southern California, 1985, 165354 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified, 1985, 165355 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Forbes Interbau Slido, 165356 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - New Orleans, 165357 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - School, West Columbia, 165358 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified/undated, 165359 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Professional, 165225
    - John Turner's Thesis, 1956, 165360 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Modern House Tour, Houston, 1957, 165361 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Brownson House, 1958, 165362 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Lecture "posters", Nov 1960, 165363 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Trial pics for student work, May 1961, 165364 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified, 1961, 165365 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Land Use Maps Computers, Jan. 1965, 165366 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Superior Oil Company, 1967, 165367 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified, 1967, 165368 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - ALSA in Portland, Berkeley, Robb Harris, June 1968, 165369 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Leonardo da Vinci Talk, Sep 1968, 165370 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Suit House Houston (1st cut), Sep 1971, 165371 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Suit House Houston (2nd cut), Sep 1971, 165372 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Haid School Chicago, Sep 1972, 165373 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Suit House, Sep 1972, 165374 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Graduation, 1972, 165375 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Brown Pavillion, MFAH, March 1974, 165376 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Hook/planning, Nov 1974, 165377 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Rice Student Work, 1974, 165378 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Unidentified, 1974, 165379 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Anthony Card Show, MFA, Jan-Feb 1976, 165380 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Pollywog to Pedagogue Lecture, 1984, 165381 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Unidentified, 1985, 165382 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Weston House, various dates, 165383 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Shadowlawn #9 and Suit House and Student Work, various dates, 165384 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - "100 Years" of Design Excellence... The 72nd Annual Michigan Society of Architects Convention presentation, 165417 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Houston Stude House, 165418 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - New Harmony Shrine, 165419 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Craig Ellwood House, 165420 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Princeton caricatures, 165421 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Senior Student Model of Settlement House, 165422 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Student work, undated, 165423 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified/undated, 165424 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified project photos, 165425 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Personal, 165226
    - Christmas 1966, 165426 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bob, Shadowlawn, farm, 1966, 165427 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Estes, Aug. 1967, 165428 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Schorre Class Party, 1967, 165429 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Christmas, 1967, 165430 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - LWS Birthday Party, 1970, 165431 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Pyramid" Old Car Museum, 1971, 165432 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified, 1971, 165433 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified, 1972, 165434 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Moon, Dec. 73, 165435 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified, 1973, 165436 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified, 1974, 165437 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Chicago, 1978, 165438 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - August 1979, 165439 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Flemings House, 1981, 165440 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified, 1984, 165441 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Picnic, yacht club trip with Fay, 165442 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified/undated, 165443 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Photos, Bayou Club, Summer 1969, 165444 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Photos with the Herds, July 9, 1972, 165445 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Unidentified photos, 1972, 165446 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - USS SC 742-A.Todd, Commandiing Officer, 165837 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Photos of Todd Home and Family, 165838 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Photos of Todd, 165839 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Unidentified, 165227
    - Buildings, 1965, 165447 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - 1974, 165448 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - 1977, 165449 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - 1988, 165450 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Building, 165451 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Loose slides (no grouping), 165452 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Uncategorized, various dates, 165453 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Photo negatives, 165454 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - 35mm Camera, 165840 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Series XI: Oversize Materials, 162241
  Arrangement
  Two oversize posters are on top of map drawer range 48-62.
  - Professional work, 162242
    - Cullinan Residence, 165559 (Drawer 150, Item 1)
    - Bolsover St. Residence, 165560 (Drawer 150, Item 2)
    - Shadowlawn, 165561 (Drawer 150, Item 3)
    - Garden Apartment Competition, 165549 (Drawer 150, Item 4)
    - Griffith Residence and Apartment, 165550 (Drawer 150, Item 5)
    - FV Thompson House, 165551 (Drawer 150, Item 6)
    - Contemporary Arts Museum, 165552 (Drawer 150, Item 7)
    - JC Walter Jr. Residence, 165553 (Drawer 150, Item 8)
    - James M. Grisebaum residence, 165554 (Drawer 150, Item 9)
    - Tsanoff House, 165555 (Drawer 150, Item 10)
    - Tridelphia Clubhouse, 165556 (Drawer 150, Item 11)
    - Winston Carter Hosue and Addition, 165557 (Drawer 150, Item 12)
    - Town and Country Cottage (Texas Housing Co.), 165558 (Drawer 150, Item 13)
    - Map of Museum District near Rice, Montrose and Main, 180194 (Drawer 150, Item 14)
    - Herman Suit, glass table, 180195 (Drawer 150, Item 15)
    - Southampton Place, 180193 (Drawer 150, Item 16)
    - Locke Lane, 180191 (Drawer 150, Item 17)
    - Richardson Residence, 180197 (Drawer 150, Item 18)
    - Longmont, 180196 (Drawer 150, Item 19)
    - Meadowlake, 180192 (Drawer 150, Item 20)
  - Unidentified drawing fragments and office ephemera, 162245 (Drawer 151, Folder 1)
  - Anderson Todd student work, 162243 (Drawer 151, Folder 2-3)
  - Rice projects (student course work and campus renovation plans), 165842 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Architectural drawings and sketches, 165920 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Non-architectural artwork and sketches, 165921 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Office ephemera, 165938 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Series XII: Addendum
  - Class prep (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Biographical (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lectures
    - Producers Council Architectural Sales Reps Institute "Architectural Education in the Land of the Lotus Eaters", 1969-10 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - University of Virginia "Texas on Display: Five New Museums", 1974-03-25 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - University of Houston School of Architecture "Morality of Logic-Logic of Morality", 1975-04-15 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - University of Texas, Austin "The Education of an Architect from Polywog to Pedagogue", 1984-04-06 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Rice University School of Architecture "From Polliwog to Pedagogue...or, the Education of an Architect", 1984-11-19 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Princeton University School of Architecture, 1996-04-12 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - University of Arkansas School of Architecture "Fay Euine Jones" (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Walter A. Netsch, Jr. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Mies van der Rohe (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - MFAH Cullinan Hall (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Nina Cullinan house (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Oral History
    Scope and Contents
    2 unedited WAV audio files recorded as part of a AIA Historic Resource Committee and University of Houston William R. Jenkins Architecture and Art Library Oral History project: Building Houston.
  - Building Economics 512 Final Exam at Princeton, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - [Rice University] Architecture Teaching Papers, 1951 - 1969 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1952 - 2013 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Events / Tributes, 1952 - 2015 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, 1958 - 2014 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - MFAH - Building Plans, Exhibit Brochures, 1958 - 1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - International Travel, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Talk Outlines for the School of Architecture, Rice University, January - February, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Phoenix Day Company Lighting Fixtures, May 1, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Rice Book List, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Shellman Notes on Creativity (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Chilean Community Facilities Program Architectural Research (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photographs (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series XIII: Obituary and memorial service, 2018-2019
  - Obituary by Jasper Scherer appearing in the Houston Chronicle, 2018-12-27 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Poem "Ode to Andy" from Class of 1974, including Sharon Perry Jachmich and Charles Alexander Berg, 1986-11-14 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Poem "The Things I Learned from Andy" by Jack McGinty (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Emails and photos from Lee Prout (B. Arch '66), James McCullar (B. Arch '63), Reto Geiser, Frank Kelly, Anne d'Olier Mullen (B. Arch '64), K.E. Rpbert Kerr (M. Arch, '56), Danny Samuels, Hans Krause,Rick Gardner, Timothy Gunther, Michael Ytterberg, 2019-01 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Video of memorial service
- Series XIV: Addendum
  - Photos of Todd, 1960s-2008 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photos of others, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Projects, 1968-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Projects: St. Mark's Episcopal Church, 1957-1958 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Projects: Butler Residence, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Projects: Superior Oil Co., Geophysical Lab, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Projects: City of Houston Fire Station 59, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Projects: Suit House, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Projects: 1924 Bolsover, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Todd-Tackett-Lacy, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1971-2014, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Rice Courses taught by Todd and others: ARCH 201, 300, 302, 400, 402, 412, 414, 415, 420, 423, 442, 500, 501, 542, 601, 602, 603, 607, 608, 610, 612, 615, 621, 623, 1958-1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - ARCH 101-102, 1971-1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - HART 205a, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - HART 206a, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - HART 319, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - School of Architecture Administration, 1948-1990 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - School of Architecture publications, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Rice Architecture Class of 1955 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Mies van der Rohe Archive, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Doodles, drawings, notes, most undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Press clippings, 1949-1978 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Research materials, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Ephemera: business cards, postcards, etc. n.d. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Set of compasses in case, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Biographical and autographical materials, 1970-2019 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Princeton class notes, sketches, correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Princeton sketches (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Princeton "Town House" senior thesis, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Princeton publications (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - U S Navy career (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rice School of Architecture (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Travel Itinerary (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Travel diary, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Travel diary, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Travel diary, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Lectures and writings, 1945-1974 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: parents, 1949-1966 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1960 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1962-2015 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence:miscellaneous, business, 1942-1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Press coverage (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Photographs: Anderson Todd (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Photographs: Anderson Todd and family (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Photographs: other (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Drawings, 1972-2020 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Drawings (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Drawings: color, 1966-2015 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Watercolors, 1952-1995 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Projects: Suit House (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Projects: Superior Oil Co. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Projects: Fire Station No. 9 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Projects: Memorial Lutheran Church (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Projects: 9 Shadowlawn (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Projects: 9 Shadowlawn brochures and drawings (Box 14, Folder 31)